我二十五歲那年
I was sheriff of this county...
是這個郡的警長
when I was 25 years old.
難以置信
Hard to believe.
我祖父是個警察 父親也是
My grandfather was a lawman. Father too.
我跟父親同時當警長
Me and him was sheriffs at the same time,
他當時在布蘭諾 而我在這
him up in Plano and me out here.
我想他一定以此為傲
I think he's pretty proud of that.
我知道我是的
I know I was.
老一輩的警長們通常連手槍也不帶
Some of the old-time sheriffs never even wore a gun.
有很多人覺得難以置信
Folks find that hard to believe.
吉姆·斯卡布羅就從未帶過槍
Jim Scarborough never carried one.
那是年輕的吉姆
That's the younger Jim.
卡曼契郡的卡司頓·伯金斯...
Gaston Boykins wouldn't wear...
也不帶槍
one up in Comanche County.
現在我總喜歡聽關於這些老前輩的事情
I always liked to hear about the old-timers.
從不想錯過一個
Never missed a chance to do so.
因此很難不把自己...
You can't help but compare yourself...
跟老前輩們作比較
against the old-timers.
也不禁好奇
Can't help but wonder...
他們那時是怎麼做到的
how they'd have operated these times.
有一個男孩是我不久之前...
There's this boy I sent to the...
在亨斯維爾這堸e他上電椅的
electric chair at Huntsville here a while back.
我親自逮捕 訊問他
My arrest and my testimony.
他殺了一個十四歲的女孩
He killed a 14-year-old girl.
報紙上寫說那是件激情犯罪
Paper said it was a crime of passion,
但是他告訴我說 根本沒有半點激情
but he told me there wasn't any passion to it.
他告訴我說它的殺人行為
Told me he'd planned to kill somebody...
都是經過長時間縝密計劃的
for as long as he could remember.
他還說要是放他出來 他還是會去殺人
Said if they turned him out, he'd do it again.
他也說他知道 他將會下地獄
Said he knew he was going to hell.
大概在那堳搕W十五分鐘
Be there in about 15 minutes.
我不明白是什麼導致這樣
I don't know what to make of that.
真的不懂
I sure do don't.
你現在看到的犯罪
The crime you see now,
也很難去採取什麼措施
it's hard to even take its measure.
不是我害怕
It's not that I'm afraid of it.
我原本就知道
I always knew you had to...
做這行本來就要有心理準備
be willing to die to even do this job.
但我不想探出頭去
But I don't want to push my chips forward and...
走出去 面對我不瞭解的東西
go out and meet something I don't understand.
有時候 男人必須暴露在風險中
A man would have to put his soul at hazard.
他只需要說:"好的
He'd have to say, "OK.
我要成為這世上的一部分"
I'll be part of this world."
是 長官 我剛進門
Yes, sir, I just walked in the door.
他身上有些東西
He had some sort of thing on him,
像是肺病病人用的氧氣筒什麼的
like a oxygen tank for emphysema or something,
一條軟管從他袖子埵虪X來
and a hose that run down his sleeve.
氧氣罐? 他拿那個幹什麼?
Oxygen tank? What the hell's he got that for?
你放心 有我在
You got me.
當你進來的時候 你就會看到了
Well, you can look at it when you get in.
我一會兒就過去
I'll be down there in a bit.
好的長官 一切在控制中
Yes, sir, I got it under control.
您好 怎麼回事?
Howdy. What's this about?
請下車 先生
Step out of the car please, sir.
那是什麼?
What is that?
我需要您下車 先生
I need you to step out of the car, sir.
- 那個是幹什麼的? - 你能不能?
- What is that for? - Would you?
能不能站著不要動 先生?
Would you hold still please, sir?
不要動
You hold still.
可惡
Shit.
水
Agua.
我沒有水
I ain't got no water.
水
Agua.
我給你說了我沒有水
I told you I ain't got no agua.
你會說英文嗎?
Do you speak English?
最後一個人呢?
Where's the last guy?
最後一個人 最後一個
Ultimo hombre, last man standing.
一定還有 他去哪了?
There must have been one. Where'd he go?
我猜想我可以從來的地方出去
I reckon I go out the way I come in.
有野狼
Hay lobos.
沒有野狼
There ain't no lobos.
要是你停下來 看著你的回頭路
You stopped to watch your backtrack.
你將會射中我
Now shoot my dumb ass.
但如果你停下來
But if you stop,
你會停在陰影處
you stopped in shade.
是的
Yeah.
我坐錯地方了麼?
My place is wrong?
你的是正座...
Yours is the first place...
丹澤和多拉會看的 如果他們...
Danzer and Dora will look if they...
如果他們知道的話
If they know.
- 皮箱堶惘酗偵? - 滿滿都是錢
- What's in the satchel? - It's full of money.
要那樣就好了
That would be the day.
你在哪弄到的手槍?
Where'd you get the pistol?
在我拿到它的地方
At the gettin' place.
- 槍是你買的嗎? - 不 是我發現的
- Did you buy that gun? - No. I found it.
- 溫利 - 什麼? 你別再發牢騷了
- Llewelyn. - What? Quit your hollering.
你拿什麼換來的?
What'd you get for that thing?
你不必樣樣都知道 卡拉·珍
You don't need to know everything, Carla Jean.
我必須知道
I need to know that.
你要是再喋喋不休
Keep running that mouth of yours,
我會把你綁起來
I'm gonna take you in the back and screw you.
- 說大話 - 繼續呀
- Big talk. - Keep it up.
很好 我不想知道
Fine. I don't want to know.
我甚至不想知道你一整天去了哪
I don't even want to know where you been all day.
那樣最好
That'll work.
好的
All right.
- 奧萊溫利 - 怎麼了?
- Llewelyn? - Yeah?
- 寶貝 你在做什麼? - 我要出去
- What're you doing, baby? - I'm going out.
去哪?
Going where?
我忘了做件事情 很快會回來
A little something I forgot to do, but I'll be back.
你要做什麼事情?
And what're you gonna do?
我要去做一件說不清的事情
I'm fixing to do something...
但現在我無論如何都要去做
dumber than hell, but I'm going anyways.
我要是沒有回來 告訴媽媽我愛她
If I don't come back, you tell Mother I love her.
你母親已經死了 奧萊溫利
Your mother's dead, Llewelyn.
好吧 那我自己告訴她
Well, then I'll tell her myself.
- 多少錢? - 69分
- How much? - Sixty-nine cents.
還有汽油?
And the gas?
一路上有下雨嗎?
Y'all getting any rain up your way?
那條路是通往哪的?
What way would that be?
我看你是從達拉斯來的
Well, I seen you was from Dallas.
我打哪來的關你啥事...
What business is it of yours where I'm from...
...老兄?
...friendo?
我什麼意思也沒有
Well, I didn't mean nothing by it.
你什麼意思也沒有?
You didn't mean nothing?
只是想打發時間而已
I was just passing the time.
如果這樣你也受不了
If you don't want to accept that,
那我不知道我還能幫你什麼
I don't know what else I can do for you.
還有什麼事情?
Will there be something else?
我不知道 會有嗎?
I don't know. Will there?
- 有什麼不對勁? - 不對勁什麼?
- Is something wrong? - With what?
任何事情?
With anything.
那就是你要問我的嗎?
Is that what you're asking me?
是否有什麼事情不對勁嗎?
Is there something wrong with anything?
還有什麼事?
Will there be anything else?
這你已經問過我了
You already asked me that.
嗯...我想我要關門了
Well, I need to see about closing now.
要關門?
See about closing?
- 是的先生 - 你幾點關門?
- Yes, sir. - What time do you close?
- 現在 就是現在關 - 現在沒說是幾點啊
- Now. We close now. - Now is not a time.
你幾點關門?
What time do you close?
大概天黑的時候 天黑就關
Generally around dark. At dark.
你不知道你在說什麼 對吧?
You don't know what you're talking about, do you?
先生?
Sir?
我說你不知道你在說什麼
I said you don't know what you're talking about.
- 你幾點鐘睡覺? - 先生?
- What time do you go to bed? - Sir?
你難道是聾子嗎?
You're a bit deaf, aren't you?
我說你幾點鐘睡覺?
I said, what time do you go to bed?
哦
Oh.
大約晚上九點半 我會說大約九點半
Somewhere around 9:30. I'd say around 9:30.
我可以那個時候再來
I could come back then.
你要再來做什麼? 我們已經關門了啊
Why would you be coming back? We'll be closed.
是啊 沒錯
Yeah, you said that.
嗯...我現在得關門了
Well, I got to close now.
你住在後面那房子嗎?
You live in that house out back?
- 是的 - 從出生就住在這嗎?
- Yes, I do. - You lived here all your life?
這是我岳父的房子 原本是
Well, this is my wife's father's place, originally.
你是招贅進來的?
You married into it?
之前我們住在德州天普市許多年
We lived in Temple, Texas for many years.
全家人都住在一起 在天普市
Raised a family there. In Temple.
大約四年前我們搬到這
We come out here about four years ago.
你是招贅進來的?
You married into it?
如果你非要這樣說的話
If that's the way you want to put it.
我沒非要這樣說
Well, I don't have some way to put it.
事情就是那樣
That's the way it is.
你玩硬幣遊戲最多輸掉多少?
What's the most you ever lost on a coin toss?
- 先生? - 你玩硬幣遊戲最多輸掉多少?
- Sir? - The most you ever lost on a coin toss?
哦 我不知道 我說不上來
Oh, I don't know. I couldn't say.
- 猜吧 - 猜?
- Call it. - Call it?
- 是的 - 為什麼?
- Yes. - For what?
只管猜
Just call it.
我們得先知道為什麼要猜
We need to know what we're calling it for here.
你必須猜 我不能幫你猜
You need to call it. I can't call it for you.
那樣不公平
Or it wouldn't be fair.
我什麼也沒有要賭
I didn't put nothing up.
不 你有
Yes, you did.
你這輩子 不就是一直在下注
You've been putting it up your whole life.
你只是不知道而已
You just didn't know it.
- 你知道這硬幣是什麼年份的嗎? - 不知道
- You know what date is on this coin? - No.
1958年 已經過去22年了 這硬幣才流浪到此
1958. It's been traveling 22 years to get here.
現在來到這 不是正面就是反面
And now it's here. And it's either heads or tails.
你必須說出來 猜吧
You have to say. Call it.
聽著... 我必須知道 猜對了我贏得什麼
Well, look, I need to know what I stand to win.
- 所有的東西 - 什麼?
- Everything. - How's that?
猜對了你就得到了一切 猜吧
You stand to win everything. Call it.
好吧 那就正面
All right. Heads, then.
很好
Well done.
- 別放到口袋去 - 什麼?
- Don't put it in your pocket. - Sir?
別放到口袋去
Don't put it in your pocket.
那是你的幸運硬幣
It's your lucky quarter.
那你要我放哪?
Where do you want me to put it?
哪堻ㄕn 就是別放口袋
Anywhere not in your pocket.
放進去跟其他硬幣混在一起
Or it'll get mixed in with the others...
它就只是個硬幣而已了
and become just a coin.
跟原本一樣了
Which it is.
奧萊溫利?
Llewelyn?
怎麼回事?
What the hell?
- 奧德薩市 - 我們為何要去奧德薩?
- Odessa. - Why would we go to Odessa?
不是我們 是你 待在你母親家
No, not we. You. You stay with your mother.
嗯 為什麼?
Well, how come?
聽著 現在是週日午夜
Look, right now it's midnight Sunday.
九個小時後 法院開始上班
Courthouse opens nine hours from now.
有人將會來查證...
Someone's gonna call in the number...
貨車檢查板上的車輛編號
on the inspection plate of my truck.
在9:30左右 他們會來這
And around 9:30, they'll show up here.
- 但是 我們要多久才能? - 什麼時候你才會放棄
- How long do we? - What point would you quit
希望得到兩百萬元的夢想?
bothering to look for your two million dollars?
我要怎樣跟媽媽說?
What am I supposed to tell Mama?
就站在門口大聲叫喊　 "媽媽 我回來了"
Stand in the door and holler, "Mama, I'm home!"?
- 奧萊溫利 - 快 將你的東西打包
- Llewelyn. - Come on, pack your things.
任何留下來的東西 將不會再見到
Anything you leave, you ain't gonna see again.
嗯 不用道歉
Well, don't fall down apologizing.
寶貝 事情已經發生
Oh, baby, things happen.
快 我無法回頭
Come on, I can't take them back.
不用腦子思考的賤人?
Mind riding bitch?
- 這是他的車嗎? - 嗯
- This his truck? - Mm-hmm.
有螺絲刀嗎?
Got a screwgie?
誰刺破他的輪胎?
Who cut his tires?
我猜是墨西哥人 不是我們的人
Mexicans, I guess. Wasn't us.
- 是一隻死狗 - 是啊
- That is a dead dog. - Yes, it is.
- 接收器在哪? - 在我這
- Where's the receiver? - I've got it.
他們都爛了
These are some ripe petunias.
拿著這個
Hold this, please.
你要這個?
Want it?
- 有接收到什麼嗎? - 一點聲響也沒
- Getting anything on this? - Not a bleep.
好吧
All right.
手電筒給我
Give me that.
- 我以為是汽車著火了呢 - 是汽車著火了
- I thought it was a car afire. - It is a car afire.
但是溫道爾說曠野地區...
Wendell said there's something...
還有些狀況
in the back country too.
進去
Step in there.
郡堶惜偵糪伬
When's the county gonna start...
才會付我馬的租金啊?
paying rent on my horse?
我越來越愛你了
I love you more and more every day.
那很好
That's very nice.
- 要小心 - 我一直是的
- Be careful. - Always am.
- 別受傷了 - 從來不會
- Don't get hurt. - Never do.
也別傷人
Don't hurt no one.
如果你這樣說的話
If you say so.
- 沒見過燒成這樣子的車 - 是 長官
- Wouldn't think a car'd burn like that. - Yes, sir.
我們該帶香腸來烤的
We should've brought wienies.
看來是一輛 77年福特 是嗎 溫道爾?
That look like about a '77 Ford to you, Wendell?
可能是
It could be.
我說一定是 絕對是
I'd say it is. Not a doubt in my mind.
這老傢伙在公路上被殺?
The old boy shot by the highway?
是 先生 他的車
Yes, sir. His vehicle.
疑犯在高速公路上殺死了...
Man killed Lamar's deputy, took his car,
埃瑪的副警長 並開走他的車
killed that man on the highway,
換開他的車 那車現在就在這
swapped for his car, now here it is...
他又不曉得換了什麼車走了
and he's swapped again for God knows what.
看來那樣很直接呀 警長
That's very linear, sheriff.
- 是呀 歲月讓人腦袋變簡單 - 是 長官
- Age'll flatten a man, Wendell. - Yes, sir.
- 但還有其他的 - 是的
- Then there's this other. - Yeah.
- 你騎溫士頓 - 你確定?
- You ride Winston. - You sure?
喔 我當然確定
Oh, I'm more than sure.
要是洛蕾塔的馬有什麼事情
If anything happens to Loretta's horse out here,
我可以告訴你
I can tell you,
我絕對承受不起
I don't want to be the party that was aboard.
來回的車痕 都是同一種輪胎的印記
It's the same tire tread coming back as going.
也是差不多時間產生的
Made about the same time too.
你可以清楚的看到輪胎的壓痕
You can see the sipes real clear.
有人將檢查板...
Somebody's pried the inspection...
從車門上撬走了
plate off the door on this one.
我知道這貨車
I know this truck.
是一個叫做摩斯的小伙子的
Belongs to a feller named Moss.
- 奧萊溫利·摩斯? - 就是他
- Llewelyn Moss? - That's the boy.
- 你覺得他是個毒癮逃犯? - 我不知道
- You figure him for a dope runner? - I don't know.
- 有點懷疑 - 槍戰就在那邊
- I kindly doubt it. - O.K. Corral is just yonder.
喔 天啊 他們連狗都射殺
Oh, hell's bells, they even shot the dog.
看起來像是交易中出了差錯 對嗎?
This is just a deal gone wrong, isn't it?
是呀 似乎是出了一兩個差錯
Yup. Appears to have been a glitch or two.
那是什麼口徑的 警長?
What calibers you got there, sheriff?
九毫米
Nine-millimeter.
還有一些0.45英吋ACP彈
Couple of.45 ACPs.
有人用霰彈槍處理了那條狗
Somebody unloaded on that thing with a shotgun.
你覺得為什麼野狼不來吃這些屍體?
How come the coyotes ain't been at them?
我不知道
I don't know.
我猜是因為它們不吃墨西哥人
Supposedly, a coyote won't eat a Mexican.
這些人看上去衣冠楚楚
These boys appear to be managerial.
我認為 我們看到的不是只有一場騷動
I think we're looking at more than one fracas.
在這埵璁D
Execution here.
在那邊決鬥
Wild West over there.
是墨西哥的褐色海洛因
It's that Mexican brown dope.
哦 這些屍體都開始浮腫了
Oh, these boys is all swole up.
所以早些時候準備交易
So this was earlier. Getting set to trade.
然後 出現了分歧...
Then, whoa, differences, and...
也許不完全是為了金錢
Might not even a been no money.
有可能
That's possible.
- 但是你不太相信 - 是啊
- But you don't believe it? - No.
也許吧
Probably I don't.
嗯 真是一場混戰 是嗎 警長?
Well, it's a mess, ain't it, sheriff?
即使當時沒有 早晚混戰也會發生的
If it ain't, it'll do till the mess gets here.
你好?
Yes, sir?
我要找奧萊溫利·摩斯
I'm looking for Llewelyn Moss.
你有去他的車那邊找過嗎?
Did you go up to his trailer?
- 有的 - 嗯 那他該去上班了
- Yes, I did. - Well, I'd say he's at work.
你要留個口信嗎?
Do you want to leave a message?
他在哪堣u作?
Where does he work?
我不能說
I can't say.
他在哪堣u作?
Where does he work?
先生 我沒有權利...
Sir, I ain't at liberty to give out...
我們居民的隱私洩漏出去
no information about our residents.
他在哪堣u作?
Where does he work?
你是聾了嗎?
Did you not hear me?
我們不能提供訊息
We can't give out no information.
為什麼要去到爾德媔?
Why all the way to Del Rio?
我要去跟羅伯特借一輛車子
I'm gonna borrow a car from Roberto.
你買不起嗎?
You can't afford one?
我不想登記
I don't want to register it.
- 聽著 幾天之內我會跟你聯絡 - 你保證?
- Look, I'll call you in a couple days. - Promise?
是的 我保證
Yes, I do.
我有不詳的預感 奧萊溫利
I got a bad feeling, Llewelyn.
我有好的預感 這樣就抵消了
I got a good one. Oughta even out.
聽著 別再這麼擔心了
Listen, you gotta quit your worrying so much.
- 媽媽一定會發狂 - 嗯
- Mama's gonna raise hell. - Mm-hm.
一定會百般的怨咒你的
She's just gonna cuss you up and down.
你應該很習以為常了吧
Well, you should be used to that.
我對很多事情都習以為常了
I'm used to lots of things.
- 我在沃爾瑪工作 - 再也不是了 卡拉·珍
- I work at Wal-Mart. - Not anymore, Carla Jean.
你退休了
You are retired.
- 奧萊溫利? - 是的 夫人?
- Llewelyn? - Yes, ma'am?
- 你會回來的 對嗎? - 我會回來的
- You are coming back, ain't you? - I shall return.
縣警署!
Sheriff's department!
看那個鎖
Look at that lock.
- 要進去嗎? - 拿出槍戒備
- We going in? - Gun out and up.
- 你的槍呢? - 我躲在你後面
- What about yours? - I'm hiding behind you.
縣警署!
Sheriff's department!
我相信他們走的很匆忙
I believe they done lit a shuck.
我相信你是對的
I believe you're right.
- 那是鎖上的嗎? - 或許是的
- That from the lock? - Probably must be.
他離開多久了 警長?
So when was he here, sheriff?
我不知道 哦...
I don't know. Oh...
- 喔 現在情況更加複雜了 - 警長?
- Now that's aggravating. - Sheriff?
仍然有水滴
Still sweating.
喔 警長 我們剛剛錯過他!
Oh, sheriff! We just missed him!
我們應該趕緊用無線電通報
We gotta circulate this on radio.
好啊
All right.
要通報些什麼?
What do we circulate?
搜尋一個最近喝牛奶的男子?
Looking for a man who has recently drunk milk?
哦 警長 情況果然更加複雜了
Oh, sheriff, that's aggravating.
那還用你說嗎
I'm ahead of you there.
你是否覺得摩斯已經知道...
Think this boy Moss has got any notion...
有一幫傢伙...
of the sorts of sons-of-bitches...
已經準備要獵殺他了?
that are hunting him?
我不知道 他應該知道的
I don't know. He ought to.
他當時看到的畫面跟我看的一樣
He's seen the same things I've seen...
當然給了我一些想法
and it certainly made an impression on me.
- 載我到旅館 - 要去哪一家呢?
- Take me to a motel. - Got one in mind?
找一家便宜的
Someplace cheap.
- 告訴我你的選擇 - 我現在怎麼做?
- You tell me the option. - Do what now?
根據價錢選擇一個你可以接受的
You pick the option goes with the applicable rate.
我只是一個人
I'm just one person,
所以 床的大小不重要
so it don't matter the size of the bed.
我是羅伯特·賽加摩爾 我不在家
This is Roberto's Automotive. I'm not in right now.
有事請留言
Please leave a message.
- 哈囉? - 奧萊溫利在嗎?
- Hello? - Is Llewelyn there?
奧萊溫利? 不在
Llewelyn? No, he ain't.
你在等他嗎?
You expect him?
我為何要等他? 你是誰?
Now why would I expect him? Who is this?
需要我幫忙嗎?
May I help you?
嗯 請問有拉堸那~牌靴子嗎?
Yeah, you got a pair of Larry Mahans?
11號的?
Shoulder, size 11?
- 我查查看 - 有賣襪子嗎?
- I'll check. - You all sell socks?
- 只有白色的 - 我也只穿白襪 請問有廁所嗎?
- Just white. - Well, white's all I wear. Bathroom?
別停下 慢慢開過那些房間
Don't stop. Just ride me up past those rooms.
- 什麼房間? - 你就載我四處看看
- What room? - Just drive me around.
我要看看這埵釣S有其他人
I wanna see if someone's here.
繼續走 別停下
Keep going. Don't stop.
老兄 我可不想被一些麻煩事纏身
I don't wanna get into some kind of a jackpot here.
沒事的
It's all right.
你為何不就在這堣U車
Why don't I just set you down right here...
我們就別再爭了
and we won't argue about it?
載我到另一家旅館
Take me to another motel.
我們的交易就到此為止吧
Let's just call it square.
聽著 你已經惹到麻煩了
You're in the jackpot,
我正試著要讓你脫離麻煩
and I'm trying to get you out of it.
載我到另一家旅館
Take me to another motel.
這是奧斯丁做的 關於公路上的男子的驗屍報告
Lab reports from Austin on that boy by the highway.
- 是哪一種子彈? - 壓根沒有子彈
- What was the bullet? - Wasn't no bullet.
- 沒有子彈? - 是 長官 完全沒有
- Wasn't no bullet? - Yes, sir. Wasn't none.
嗯 溫道爾 恕我冒昧
Well, Wendell, with all due respect,
這一點也說不通啊
that don't make a lot of sense.
是的 長官
No, sir.
你說前額有一個被打入的創面 沒有打出來的創面
You said entry wound in the forehead, no exit wound.
- 是的 長官 - 那你是不是在說
- Yes, sir. - You telling me he shot this boy
槍手擊中了那男子的頭部 然後用小刀 將子彈給挖出來?
and then went digging around with a knife?
- 長官 我不想這樣設想 - 我也不想!
- Sir, I don't wanna picture that. - I don't either.
需要加點咖啡嗎 警長?
Can I freshen that there for you, sheriff?
好啊 莫林 早該加了
Yeah, Maureen, you better had.
巡警隊跟緝毒署探員 今天早上將會去現場
Ranger and the DEA are headed back out to the scene.
你要跟他們一起去嗎?
Gonna join 'em?
那邊有發現新的屍體嗎?
Any new bodies accumulate out there?
- 沒有 長官 - 那好 我想我可以不去了
- No, sir. - Well, then I guess I can skip it.
十二口徑獵槍 需要子彈嗎?
Twelve-gauge. You need shells?
是的 當然了
Yeah, double-ought.
他們的震撼力會讓你喜歡的
Yeah, that'll give you a wallop.
你這埵魚磎S營用品嗎?
Y'all got camping supplies?
帳篷桿 你已經有帳篷了嗎?
Tent poles. You already have the tent?
算是有吧
Well, something like that.
嗯 你告訴我帳篷的型號
Give me the model number on the tent,
我可以幫你訂貨
I can order poles.
- 算了 我要買個帳篷 - 哪種的?
- Never mind. I want a tent. - What kind?
有最多根帳篷桿的那種
The kind with most poles.
我可以再訂一個房間嗎?
Could I get another room?
你要換別的房間?
You wanna change rooms?
不 女士
No, ma'am,
我要多一間房間
I wanna keep my room and get another one.
- 額外的一間? - 是的 女士
- Another additional? - Yes, ma'am.
你有旅館房間的平面圖嗎?
And do you have a map of the rooms?
有 我們有
Well, yeah, we had a sorta one.
哦 謝謝
Oh, thank you.
38 號房如何?
How about 38?
嗯 若是你要的話...
Well, you can have the one right...
可以選隔壁的一間 137 號 沒有人住
next to yours if you want, 137. It ain't took.
不要 38號房可以
No, 38 will be fine.
那間有兩張雙人床
Well, that's got two double beds.
你們怎麼找到的?
How'd you find that?
你不該這樣做的
You shouldn't be doin' that.
即使像你這樣的年輕人
Even a young man like you.
- 不應該做什麼? - 搭便車
- Doin' what? - Hitchhiking.
太危險了
Dangerous.
你認得安通·希格爾 對嗎?
You know Anton Chigurh by sight, is that correct?
是 先生 我瞭解他各個方面
Yes, sir, I know him every which way.
你上次見他是什麼時候?
When did you last see him?
呃...
Uh...
...去年11月28號
...November 28th, last year.
你似乎把這日期記得特別清楚 我有要你坐下嗎?
Seem pretty sure of the date. Did I ask you to sit?
沒有 先生 但你教過我
No, sir, but you struck me as a man...
要成為一個不要浪費椅子的男人
who wouldn't wanna waste a chair.
我對日期 人名 數字記憶力特好
I remember dates, names, numbers.
我上次見到他是11月28日
I saw him November the 28th.
現在我們要面對一個 我行我素不顧後果的人
Got a loose cannon here.
我們還損失了一大票金錢
We're out a bunch of money,
還有另一組人馬也在覬覦
and the other party is out his product.
- 是 先生 - 這個帳戶每24小時
- Yes, sir. - This account will give up $1,200
最多可提領一千兩百美元 一次最多可以提領一千美元
in any 24-hour period. That's up from a thousand.
要是你的花費比這個高
If your expenses run higher,
我希望你值得我們信任
I hope you'll trust us for it.
好的
OK.
你有多瞭解希格爾?
Just how well do you know Chigurh?
你要瞭解些什麼?
What do you wanna know?
我要知道你對他的看法 整體的看法
I just wanna know your opinion of him, in general.
也就是他有多麼危險?
Just how dangerous is he?
跟什麼來比較? 跟黑死病嗎?
Compared to what, the bubonic plague?
對我來說 他實在是夠壞了
He's bad enough you called me.
是啊 他是個喪心病狂殺手 那又如何?
Yeah, he's a psychopathic killer, but so what?
世界上這種人多的是
There's plenty of them around.
他昨天在爾德媔曭漁館殺死了三個人
Killed three men in a Del Rio motel yesterday,
還有在那沙漠野外...
and two others in that colossal...
另外殺了兩個
goat-fuck out in the desert.
- 我們可以阻止他的 - 你似乎對自己很有信心
- We can stop that. - Seem pretty sure of yourself.
你過去的日子 似乎過得還不錯
You've led something of a charmed life,
是嗎 威爾斯先生?
haven't you, Mr. Wells?
老實說 我認為我的生活如何
In all honesty, I can't say that...
跟這些一點關係也沒有
charm has had a whole lot to do with it.
- 我在想... - 什麼?
- I was wondering... - Yes?
你可以讓我的停車證恢復有效嗎?
Could you validate my parking ticket?
- 我想 你是在開玩笑吧 - 抱歉
- An attempt at humor, I suppose? - I'm sorry.
你知道嗎 我算了算...
You know, I counted the floors...
這棟大樓的樓層
to this building from the street.
- 怎樣? - 少了一層樓
- And? - There's one missing.
我們會深入檢查
We'll look into it.
一個房間 住一晚
One room. One night.
- 總共26美金 - 好的
- That'll be $26. - Alrighty.
整個晚上你都在嗎?
You on all night?
是 先生
Yes, sir,
我到明天十點鐘才下班
I'll be right here till 10:00 in the morning.
這是給你的
This here's for you.
我不會要你做非法的事情
Now, I ain't asking you to do anything illegal.
有個人一直在找我 不是警察
There's someone who been looking for me. Not police.
若是有人晚上來住宿 請立刻告訴我
You just call me if anyone else checks in tonight.
任何人 不管是任何人來住宿都要
And by anyone, I mean any swinging dick.
絕對不可能
There just ain't no way.
別擔心 我不會傷害你
Don't worry, I ain't gonna hurt you.
我需要你載我離開這
I need you to drive me on outta here.
- 為什麼不? - 我不知道 哥們
- Why not? - I don't know, man.
你遇到車禍了嗎?
Were you in a car accident?
我用500美金買你的外套
I'll give you 500 bucks for that coat.
錢給我看一下
Lemme see the money.
你遇到車禍了嗎?
Were you in a car accident?
- 是的 - 給我錢
- Yeah. - OK, give me the money.
錢就在這 給我外套
It's right here. Give me the clothes.
讓他拿著錢
Let him hold the money.
給你
Give it here.
啤酒也給我
Gimme that beer too.
多少錢?
How much?
布來恩 啤酒給他
Brian, give him the beer.
醫院...
Medico...
...請幫我
...por favor.
守在這!
Wait up!
有那些車輛的新發現嗎?
Any word on those vehicles yet?
警長 我發現所有事情 都等待我們去調查
Sheriff, I found out everything there was to find.
那些車輛...
Those vehicles are titled...
都登記在死人名下
and registered to deceased people.
那輛飆馬車車主已經死了二十年了
The owner of that Bronco's been dead 20 years.
你要我去查其他那些墨西哥人嗎?
Want me to find out about the Mexican ones?
不了 不用
No. Lord, no.
這是這個月的支票
There's this month's checks.
緝毒署的探員又打電話來了
That DEA agent called again.
你還是不跟他們談嗎?
You don't wanna talk to him?
我會試著盡我所能撐著
Gonna try to keep from it much as I can.
他要再次去現場 他問你...
Going back. Wanted to know...
是否要跟他一起去
if you wanted to go with him.
他是衷心的說
That's cordial of him.
你可以幫我打電話給洛蕾塔
Can I get you to call Loretta,
告訴他我要去奧德薩市 去找卡拉·珍·摩斯?
tell her I'm going to Odessa to see Carla Jean Moss?
- 是的 警長 - 我到了 再打電話給她
- Yes, sheriff. - I'll call her when I get there.
我本現在就可以打
I'd call now,
可是她會要我回家
but if she want me to come home, I might.
你要我等你 等到你離開這媔?
Do you want me to wait till you quit the building?
非到萬不得已
Don't wanna lie without...
絕對不要說謊話
what it's absolutely necessary.
托伯特說過的 真理與正義的意義是什麼?
What is it Torbert says about truth and justice?
喔 我們每天自我反省一次
Oh, we dedicate ourselves daily anew.
好像這樣吧
Something like that.
我想 我將要每天自我反省兩次
I'm gonna commence dedicating myself twice daily.
在事情結束之前 也許還會反省個三次
Might come to three before it's over.
怎麼回事?
What the hell?
警長?
Sheriff?
最近你有檢查過載運的物品嗎?
You looked at your load lately?
這已經違規了
That is a damn outrage.
有一條繩子的結鬆了
One of those tie-downs worked loose.
你原本運載了幾具屍體?
How many bodies did you leave with?
我一具也沒有丟失呀 警長
I ain't lost none of 'em, sheriff.
你們就不能用有蓋貨車來載運嗎?
Couldn't y'all have taken a van out there?
因為沒有一部四輪傳動的貨車
We didn't have no van with four-wheel drive.
你會開給我貨物捆綁不牢的罰單嗎?
You gonna write me up for improperly secured load?
你快給我滾吧
You get your ass outta here.
你好 早安
Buenos dias.
我在想 這應該不是...
I'm guessing this isn't...
你曾經想過的樣子吧
the future you had pictured for yourself
當你第一眼見到那些錢的時候
when you first clapped eyes on that money.
別擔心 我不是那個要追殺你的人
Don't worry. I'm not the man who's after you.
我知道
I know that.
我見過他
I've seen him.
你見過他? 而且你沒有死?
You've seen him? And you're not dead?
嗯
Huh.
那傢伙是怎樣的 超級壞蛋嗎?
What's this guy supposed to be, the ultimate badass?
不要認為我會這樣形容他
Don't think that's how I'd describe him.
那你怎樣形容他?
How would you describe him?
我想我會說他沒有幽默感
I guess I'd say he doesn't have a sense of humor.
- 他叫做希格爾 - 修格?
- His name's Chigurh. - Sugar?
希格爾 安通·希格爾
Chigurh. Anton Chigurh.
你知道他怎樣找到你嗎?
You know how he found you?
我知道他怎樣找到我的
Yeah, I know how he found me.
那是個發訊機
It's called a transponder.
我知道那是什麼
I know what it's called.
- 他不再會找到我了 - 不會用那種方式
- He won't find me again. - Not that way.
- 不會用任何方式 - 花了我大約三個小時
- Not any way. - Took me about three hours.
嗯 這期間我一直動不了
Yeah, well, I been immobile.
不 你不瞭解
No. You don't understand.
- 你的職業是什麼? - 我退休了
- What do you do? - I'm retired.
- 你曾經是做什麼的? - 焊工
- What did you do? - Welder.
- 電焊? 水下焊接? 不袗焊? - 都算是
- Acetylene? Mig? Tig? - Any of it.
- 只要是能焊接的 我都行 - 鑄鐵?
- If it can be welded, I can weld it. - Cast iron?
- 可以 - 我不是說銅焊
- Yeah. - I don't mean braze.
- 我沒說銅焊 - 銅鉛合金?
- I didn't say braze. - Pot metal?
我不是說過了嗎?
What did I say?
- 你有去過越南? - 是的 我有
- Were you in 'Nam? - Yeah, I was 'Nam.
我也有
So was I.
所以 這能說明什麼 我是你兄弟?
So, what does that make me, your buddy?
聽著 你得把錢給我
Look, you gotta give me this money.
我沒有理由再保護你了
I got no other reason to protect you.
太遲了 我花完了
It's too late. I spent it.
150萬在酒與色上
A million and a half on whores and whiskey,
剩下的全花在了這個醫院
and the rest of it, I just sorta blew it in.
你怎麼知道他不會去奧德薩市?
How do you know he's not on his way to Odessa?
- 他為何要去奧德薩市? - 去殺你老婆
- Why would he go to Odessa? - Kill your wife.
或許他才是那個...
Maybe he's the one that needs to be worried...
要擔心我的人
about me.
他不是的
He isn't.
你還是沒搞清楚
Yeah. You're not cut out for this.
你只是個剛好路過
You're just a guy...
發現那些車子的傢伙
who happened to find those vehicles.
我住在河對岸的老鷹旅館
I'm across the river at the Hotel Eagle.
卡爾森·威爾斯
Carson Wells.
當你想通了 記得找我
Call me when you've had enough.
我甚至可以讓你保有少部份錢
I can even let you keep a little of the money.
要談交易的話
If I was into cutting deals,
我何不直接跟希格爾交易就好了?
why wouldn't I deal with Sugar?
不 不 你不明白
No, no, you don't understand.
你沒法跟他談交易
You can't make a deal with him.
即使你還他錢
Even if you gave him the money,
他還是會殺了你 只因為你造成的種種不便
he'd still kill you for inconveniencing him.
他是個特殊的人
He's a peculiar man.
也可說是有原則的人
Might even say he has principles,
他處理金錢 毒品...
principles that transcend money or drugs
所有事情 都是一樣的原則 他不像你
or anything like that. Not like you.
是的 他甚至也不像我
Yeah. He's not even like me.
他說話沒你多
No, he don't talk as much as you.
這點我比較欣賞他
I give him points for that.
卡拉·珍 很感謝你能來
Carla Jean, thank you for coming.
不知道為何要來
Don't know why I did.
我說過 我不知道他在哪
I told you, I don't know where he is.
- 你連他的消息也沒有? - 一點也沒有
- You haven't heard from him? - No, I ain't.
- 什麼都沒有? - 一句話也沒有
- Nothing? - Not word one.
有了他的消息 你會告訴我嗎?
Would you tell me if you had?
嗯 我不知道
Well, I don't know.
他不需要因你再惹麻煩
He don't need any trouble from you.
惹他麻煩的人不是我
It ain't me he's in trouble with.
那又是誰?
Who's he in trouble with then?
一些壞蛋
Some pretty bad people.
這些壞蛋會殺死他
These people will kill him,
卡拉·珍 他們不會停手
Carla Jean. They won't quit.
他也不會 他從不放棄
He won't neither. He never has.
他來者不懼
He can take all comers.
你聽過住在山德森...
You know Charlie Walser's got...
東部地區的查理·華瑟嗎?
that place out east of Sanderson?
你知道他如何宰牛嗎?
You know how he used to slaughter beeves,
先用大木槌敲暈...
hit 'em right there with a maul,
綁起來之後 再切斷喉嚨
truss 'em and slit their throats?
曾經查理把一隻牛五花大綁
Charlie's got one all trussed up,
準備把它力氣耗盡...
all set to drain him...
這隻牛到處翻跳扭動
and the beef comes to, thrashing around.
那可是有六百磅種的畜生啊
Six hundred pounds of very pissed off livestock.
原諒我的措辭... 然而...
You'll excuse the... Well...
查理抓起槍對準發狂的牛的頭部射
Charlie grabs a gun, shoot the thing in the head,
但是 那隻牛四處搖晃 亂衝亂跳
but with the swinging and thrashing,
並沒射中
it's a glance shot.
子彈反彈射傷了查理的肩膀
Ricochets, hits Charlie in the shoulder.
你去看看查理
You go see Charlie,
現在的他仍然無法舉起右手拿帽子
he still can't pick up his right hand for his hat.
我想說的是
The point being,
即使是牛與人的競賽...
that even in the contest between man and steer,
結果也不是一定的
the issue is not certain.
奧萊溫利打給你時
When Llewelyn calls,
請告訴他 我會保護他的安全
just tell him I can make him safe.
當然 今天屠宰牛的方法...
'Course, they slaughter steers...
大不相同了
a lot different these days.
使用空氣槍 射出一塊小石子
Use a air gun. Shoots out a little rod...
只能進到腦部那麼深
about that far under the brain.
然後吸出來
Sucks right back in.
畜生永遠不知道被什麼射中
Animal never knows what hit him.
你告訴我這些要做什麼 警長?
Why are you telling me that, sheriff?
我不知道
I don't know.
我有點失神了
My mind wanders.
哈囉 卡爾森
Hello, Carson.
我們去你房間
Let's go to your room.
我們不需要這樣
You don't have to do this.
我只是一個投機者 可以現在就打道回府
I'm a day trader. I could just go home.
- 你可以 - 我會讓你感到值得
- You could. - Make it worth your while,
帶你去提款機 還有一千四百塊
take you to an ATM. There's 14 grand in it.
然後 大家各走各的
And everybody just walks away.
提款機
An ATM.
我知道提箱在哪
I know where the satchel is.
你要是知道 一定會帶在身邊
If you knew, you would have it with you.
我能在河岸找到
I can find it from the river bank.
我知道它在哪
I know where it is.
- 我知道一些更好的 - 什麼?
- I know something better. - What's that?
它將會在哪
Where it's going to be.
- 哪? - 它會被帶到我這
- Where's that? - It will be brought to me
放在我的腳邊
and placed at my feet.
你根本不確定
You don't know to a certainty.
二十分鐘之內它就可以在這
In 20 minutes it could be here.
我確定我知道
I do know to a certainty.
你知道接下來會怎樣嗎 卡爾森?
And you know what's gonna happen now, Carson?
你得承認你現在的情勢
You should admit your situation.
接下來將會更莊重
There would be more dignity in it.
你去下地獄吧
You go to hell.
好吧 我問你件事情
All right. Let me ask you something.
假使你遵循的法則 將你帶到這
If the rule you followed brought you to this,
那麼法則又有何用?
of what use was the rule?
你知道你有多瘋狂嗎?
Do you have any idea how crazy you are?
你是說 我們這段對話的內容嗎?
You mean the nature of this conversation?
我是說你這個人
I mean the nature of you.
你...你可以擁有這些錢 安通
You... You can have the money, Anton.
- 哈囉? - 是的?
- Hello? - Yes?
呃 卡爾森·威爾斯在嗎?
Is, uh, Carson Wells there?
從你的角度來說是不在了
Not in the sense that you mean.
- 你必須來見我 - 你是誰?
- You need to come see me. - Who is this?
你知道我是誰
You know who it is.
你該跟我談談
You need to talk to me.
我不需要跟你談
I don't need to talk to you.
我想你需要
I think you do.
你知道我要去哪媔?
Do you know where I'm going?
我不管你要去哪
Why would I care where you're going?
我知道你在哪
I know where you are.
是嗎? 我在哪?
Yeah, where am I?
你在河對岸的醫院
You're in the hospital across the river,
但我不是要去那
but that's not where I'm going.
你知道我要去哪嗎?
Do you know where I'm going?
- 是的 我知道你要去哪 - 好的
- Yeah, I know where you're going. - All right.
你知道 她不會在那堣F
You know she won't be there.
她在不在那堣ㄜ垠n
It doesn't make any difference where she is.
那麼 你去那邊要做什麼?
So, what're you going up there for?
你知道事情會怎樣進行下去 對嗎?
You know how this is gonna turn out, don't you?
不
Nope.
我想你知道 所以我的提議是這樣的
I think you do. So this is what I'll offer.
你帶錢來 我讓她走
You bring me the money, and I'll let her go.
否則她就跟你一樣 要對事情負責
Otherwise, she's accountable, the same as you.
這將是你最好的選擇了
That's the best deal you're gonna get.
我不說你可以拯救自己
I won't tell you you can save yourself,
因為你做不到
because you can't.
是呀 我該帶些東西給你的
Yeah, I'm gonna bring you something, all right.
我決定給你個特殊計劃
Decided to make you a project of mine.
你根本用不著來找我
You ain't gonna have to come look for me at all.
- 爾德媔曭漁館? - 是 長官
- The motel in Del Rio? - Yes, sir.
三個死者都沒有身份
None of the three had ID on 'em,
但是他們告訴我 三個都是墨西哥人
but they're tellin' me that all three is Mexican...
曾經是墨西哥人
was Mexicans.
有個問題
There's a question,
他們會停手嗎? 何時停手?
whether they stopped being and when.
是 長官
Yes, sir.
溫道爾 你查過那個鎖頭了嗎?
Wendell, did you inquire about the lock cylinder?
- 是 長官 是整個被衝出去的 - 很好
- Yes, sir. It was punched out. - OK.
你要過去看看麼?
Wanna drive out there?
不 我該查的就是如此了
No, that's all I had to look for,
看起來他們都是自然死亡
it sound like these boys died of natural causes.
怎麼會 警長?
How's that, sheriff?
就跟他們日常的工作一樣而已
Natural to the line of work they in.
- 是 長官 - 天啊 溫道爾 這簡直是全面戰爭
- Yes, sir. - My God, Wendell, it's all-out war.
我想不出其他形容詞了
I can't think of any other word for it.
這些傢伙是誰?
Who are these people?
這婸﹞W周...
Here, last week they found...
他們發現一對夫婦
this couple out in California.
在加州 他們將房間出租給老人
They rent out rooms to old people,
殺了他們 將他們埋在院子
kill 'em, bury 'em in the yard,
再將他們的社會福利金支票兌現
cash their Social Security checks.
他們先折磨被害人 我不知道為什麼
Oh, they'd torture 'em first. I don't know why.
也許他們的電視機壞了
Maybe their television set was broke.
這件事一直持續到 這塈琩茪犍峇@下:
And this went on until, here, I quote,
"當一個只套著套狗項圈的男人...
"Neighbors were alerted...
從屋媔]出來時
when a man ran from the premises
鄰居們才發覺了事情的異常"
wearing only a dog collar."
這種事情 你一定編不出來
You can't make up such a thing as that.
我敢保證
I dare you to try.
但你要注意 那就是有效果
But that's what it took, you notice,
引起人們的注意
to get somebody's attention.
在後院挖墳墓卻不會有如此效果
Digging graves in the backyard didn't bring any.
沒關係 有時候我也會一個人傻笑
Well, that's all right. I laugh myself sometimes.
你能做的事情 其實不多
Ain't a whole lot else you can do.
說說看
Tell me something.
你覺得 誰可以經由這個門進入美國?
Who gets through this gate into the United States?
我不知道 美國公民?
I don't know. American citizens?
某些美國公民 你覺得誰可以決定?
Some American citizens. Who do you think decides?
- 嗯 你可以 我猜 - 沒錯
- You do, I reckon. - That is correct.
- 我如何決定? - 我不知道
- How do I decide? - I don't know.
我問問題 我若是得到滿意回答
I ask questions. If I get sensible answers,
他們就能進入美國
then they get to go to America.
若不滿意 他們就不可以通過
If I don't, they don't.
- 關於那還有什麼不明白的嗎? - 沒有 長官
- Anything you don't understand? - No.
那我再問你一次
I ask again,
你怎麼沒穿衣服出現在這?
how you come to be here with no clothes?
我有穿外套啊
Well, I got an overcoat on.
- 你在耍我嗎? - 喔 沒有 長官
- Are you jacking with me? - No, sir.
- 別耍我 - 是的 長官
- Don't jack with me. - Yes, sir.
- 你還在當兵嗎? - 不 長官 我是退伍軍人
- You in the service? - No, I'm a veteran.
- 越南? - 是的 長官 派駐過兩次
- 'Nam? - Yes, sir, two tours.
- 哪個部隊? - 第十二步兵營
- What outfit? - Twelfth Infantry Battalion,
1966年8月7日到1968年6月2日
August 7th, 1966, July 2nd, 1968.
- 威爾遜! - 是 長官!
- Wilson! - Yes, sir!
找人來幫這位先生
Get someone to help this man.
他需要進城
He needs to get into town.
- 那些穿得習慣嗎? - 喔 還好
- How those Larry's holdin' up? - Good, good.
- 我需要一些其他的東西 - 好的
- I need everything else. - OK.
你常常見到沒穿衣服的人...
Have a lot of people come in here...
來你店堶捷?
without any clothes on?
不 不常見
No, sir. It's unusual.
她不想跟你說話
She don't want to talk to you.
不 她想的 讓她聽
Yes, she does. Put her on.
- 你知道現在幾點鐘嗎? - 我不管現在幾點
- Do you know what time it is? - I don't care,
別掛掉電話
and don't you hang up this phone.
被不中用的女婿折騰得團團轉
Discombobulated by a no-account son-in-law.
- 奧萊溫利 - 嘿
- Llewelyn? - Hey, you.
- 我該怎麼做? - 你知道發生什麼事嗎?
- What should I do? - You know what's going on?
我不知道
I don't know.
特雷爾郡的警長來找我 他...
I had the sheriff here from Terrell County. He...
你跟他說了什麼?
What'd you tell him?
我什麼都不知道怎麼跟他說?
What did I know to tell him?
你受傷了對不對?
You're hurt, ain't you?
你怎會這樣想?
What makes you say that?
從你的聲音聽出來的
I can hear it in your voice.
你的聲音在撒謊!
It's falseness in his voice!
聽著 我要你到...
Look, I want you to meet me...
愛爾帕索的沙漠旅館見我
at the Desert Sands Motel in El Paso.
因為這些錢我要給你 讓你坐上飛機
I'm gonna give you the money, put you on a plane.
奧萊溫利 我不會棄你於危難之中
Llewelyn, I ain't gonna leave you in the lurch.
不 這樣比較好
This works better.
你離開 而我又沒有錢
With you gone and I don't have the money,
他就拿我沒辦法了 但我可以好好對付他
he can't touch me, but I can sure touch him.
一旦我找到了他 我就跟你會合
And after I find him, I'll come and join you.
找誰? 我母親怎麼辦?
Find who? What am I supposed to do with mother?
- 不 她不會有事 - 她不會有事?
- She'll be all right. - All right?
不會有事? 我得了癌癥!
Be all right? I got the cancer!
沒有人會打擾她
Ain't nobody gonna bother her.
你是誰?
Who are you?
- 我? - 是的
- Me? - Yes.
誰都不是
Nobody.
會計
Accounting.
他給了墨西哥人一個接收器
He gave the Mexicans a receiver.
他覺得...
He feels...
曾經覺得越多人尋找...
He felt that the more people looking...
那很蠢 你選對工具了
That's foolish. You pick the one right tool.
我知道了
I see.
你會殺我嗎?
Are you going to shoot me?
看情況
That depends.
你有見到我嗎?
Do you see me?
我總是會見到日後發生的事情
I always seen this is what it'd come to.
三年前我就預見了這一刻
Three years ago, I pre-visioned it.
我們結婚都還沒滿三年呢
It ain't three years we been married.
三年前 我就跟他們說過...
Three years ago I said them very words,
"不" 和 "好的"
"no" and "good."
現在我們來了 九十度高溫
Here we are, 90 degree heat,
我得了癌癥 還有...
I got the cancer and look at this,
連家也沒了
not even a home to go to.
我們要去德州愛爾帕索
We're going to El Paso, Texas.
你知道我在德州愛爾帕索 認識多少人嗎?
You know how may people I know in El Paso, Texas?
- 不知道 - 就這麼多
- No, ma'am. - That's how many.
- 我沒看到我的哮喘藥 - 我放進去了 媽媽
- I didn't see my prednisone. - I put it in, Mama.
我就是沒見到
Well, I didn't see it.
嗯 我放進去了 在那個堶
Well, I put it in that one.
你先在那呆著
You just set there.
我去買票 再弄輛推車裝行李
I'll get tickets and a cart for the bags.
女士 需要我幫你提行李嗎?
You need help with the bags, madam?
嗯 謝天謝地
Well, thank God,
西德州還有紳士
there is one gentleman left in west Texas.
好的 謝謝 我又老又病
Yes, thank you. I am old and I am not well!
你們要搭哪部巴士?
Which bus are you taking?
我們要去愛爾帕索 別問我原因
Going to El Paso, don't ask me why.
很少見到墨西哥人穿西裝
It's not often you see a Mexican in a suit.
你要去愛爾帕索? 我知道那
You go to El Paso? I know it.
你們要待在哪?
Where are you staying?
哦...
Oh...
卡拉·珍 還好嗎?
Carla Jean, how are you?
警長 查理·華瑟的故事是真的嗎?
Sheriff, was that a true story about Charlie Walser?
查理·華瑟是誰? 啊! 哦...
Who's Charlie Walser? Uh! Oh...
嗯...
Um...
是真的 細節我不敢保證
True story. I couldn't swear to every detail,
但那的確是一個故事
but it's certainly true it is a story.
嗯 好吧
Yeah, right.
警長 你可以給我個保證嗎?
Sheriff, can you give me your word on something?
可以的 夫人
Yes, ma'am.
要是我告訴你奧萊溫利要去哪
If I tell you where Llewelyn's headed,
請答應我 只有你...
you promise it'll be just you...
去找他 跟他談? 只有你
who goes and talks with him? You and nobody else.
當然 我保證
Yes, ma'am, I do.
奧萊溫利從不會求助他人
Llewelyn would never ask for help.
他從不覺得需要幫助
He never thinks he needs any.
卡拉·珍 我絕不會傷害你的丈夫
Carla Jean, I will not harm your man.
況且他需要幫助 不管他知道否
And he needs help, whether he knows it or not.
兄弟 什麼問題?
What's the problem there, neighbor?
那會失去些動力 過度使用
Yep, that'll suck some power, over time.
你住附近嗎?
You from around here?
我從出生就再這
Yeah, Alpine, born and bred.
- 可以了 - 你會用哪個機場?
- Here you go. - What airport would you use?
- 機場還是小型飛機場? - 機場
- Well, airport or airstrip? - Airport.
- 嗯 你要去哪? - 我不知道
- Well, where you goin'? - I don't know.
只是到處跑 嗯?
Just lightin' out for the territories, huh?
兄弟 我也曾經如此
Brother, I been there.
嗯 有一個小型機場
Well, there's airstrips.
機場在愛爾帕索
The airport is El Paso.
若是要去比較特殊的地方
If you want someplace specific,
最好開車去...
you might could be better off...
達拉斯 就不用轉機了
just driving to Dallas, not have to connect.
兄弟 你不把它夾上去麼?
You gonna clamp them, buddy?
你可以將那些雞籠子從車上弄走麼?
Can you get those chicken crates out of the bed?
你在說些什麼啊?
What are you talking about?
嘿 體育用品先生
Hey, Mr. Sportin' Goods.
- 嘿 你好 - 你是運動員?
- Hey, yourself. - You a sport?
是的
Yeah, that's me.
我房間埵陸鈰s
I got beers in my room.
- 哦 呃 我...我在等我妻子 - 哦
- Oh, uh, I'm... I'm waiting on my wife. - Oh.
難怪你一直往窗外望?
That's who you keep looking out the window for?
- 猜對一半 - 那另一半原因呢?
- Well, half. - What else then?
- 看看有什麼情況 - 是啊
- Just looking for what's comin'. - Yeah.
但是沒有人可以預見沒發生的事
But no one ever sees that.
啤酒 就是接下來的事
Beer! That's what's comin'.
我會將冰桶拿來這 你可以繼續保持你的婚姻
I'll bring the ice chest out. You can stay married.
不了 女士 我知道 啤酒會帶來什麼
No, ma'am, I know what beer leads to.
啤酒會只會帶來更多啤酒
Beer leads to more beer.
你還好麼?
You all right?
快報警
Call the police.
通知這堛瘧給
Your local law enforcement.
我的無線電頻率不同
I'm not on their radio.
我見到了他的女兒...
I met his daughter at the...
你回家前 我可以請你喝杯咖啡嗎?
Buy you a cup of coffee 'fore you drive home?
錢沒在他房間?
No money in his room there?
他身上有幾百塊錢
Couple hundred, on his person.
那些西班牙人可能將錢藏起來了
Those hombres would have taken the stash.
我猜是這樣
I suppose so.
雖然他們來去匆匆
Though they was leavin' in a hurry.
一切都因為那錢而起 愛德·湯姆
It's all the goddamn money, Ed Tom.
金錢和毒品
Money and the drugs.
超乎其他所有事情
It's just goddamn beyond everything.
那代表什麼? 它又會帶來什麼後果?
What's it mean? What's it leading to?
你知道麼 要是你二十年前告訴我
You know, if you'd have told me 20 years ago
現在的我會看到在德州的城
I'd see children walking the streets of our Texas towns
孩子們染者綠色頭髮 穿著鼻環走來走去
with green hair, bones in their noses,
我只是直截了當地不相信你
I just flat-out wouldn't have believed you.
神跡奇事
Signs and wonders.
但我認為一旦不尊稱人們...
But I think once you quit hearing...
"先生"與"女士" 其他的壞事很快會接踵而來
"sir" and "ma'am," the rest is soon to foller.
- 喔 那就是潮流 - 是啊
- Oh, it's the tide. - Yeah.
令人悲傷的潮流 還不只是這樣
It's the dismal tide. It is not the one thing.
不只是這樣而已
Not the one thing.
然而 那都不足以解釋 你要逮捕的那個人
Yeah, well, none of that explains your man, though.
他只是一個嗜殺成性的瘋子 愛德·湯姆
Well, he's just a goddamn homicidal lunatic, Ed Tom.
我不確定他是一個瘋子
I'm not sure he's a lunatic.
嗯 那你覺得他是什麼?
Well, what would you call him?
嗯 有時我甚至覺得他像個鬼魂
Well, sometimes I think he's pretty much a ghost.
- 他是真實的 好麼? - 是嗎?
- He's real, all right. - Oh, yeah?
是的 在老鷹旅館發生的事情
Yeah. All of that over at the Eagle Hotel?
超乎想像
Just beyond everything.
是啊 他有些無情
Yeah. Got some hard bark on him.
幾乎不能這麼說
Why... Well, that don't hardly say it.
有天 他射殺了旅館櫃檯人員
He shoots a desk clerk one day,
走回來又接著...
walks right back in the next...
射殺了一個退役陸軍上校
and shoots a retired Army colonel.
真是難以置信
It's hard to believe.
最後還回到犯罪現場
Just strolls right back into a crime scene.
有誰會做這樣的事情?
Now, who'd do such a thing?
你又能怎樣防範?
How do you defend against it?
旅途平安 愛德·湯姆
Well, good trip, Ed Tom.
很抱歉我們沒能幫他
Sorry we couldn't help your boy.
- 我在後面! - 你怎知道我在這?
- In back! - How'd you know I was here?
誰會開你那輛車?
Who else'd be driving up in your truck?
- 你聽見了? - 如何?
- You heard it? - How's that?
你聽說過我的事 你在取笑我嗎?
Did you hear my? You're having fun with me.
你怎會這樣子想呢?
What give you that idea?
我看到其中一隻貓聽見車聲
I seen one of the cats heard it.
但你怎麼知道那是我的車?
How'd you know it was my truck?
當你走進來的時候我推論的
I deduced it when you walked in.
那些你現在有幾隻?
How many of them things you got now?
貓? 我不知道 好幾隻吧
Cats? Oh, I don't know, several.
嗯 得看你說的"有"是什麼意思了
Well, it depends on what you mean by "got."
有些是半野生的
Some of 'em are half wild,
也有些是野貓
some of 'em are just outlaws.
- 還好嗎 埃奡? - 你這不是見到了
- How you been, Ellis? - You're looking at it.
我要說你看起來老了許多
I got to say, you're looking older.
我的確老了
I am older.
我收到了你老婆的信
Got a letter from your wife.
她經常寫信給我
She writes me pretty regular,
讓我知道些家堛漁灡
keeps me up on the family news.
我不知道有什麼消息
Didn't know there was any.
她說你要辭職了
Told me you're quittin'.
- 要喝一杯麼? - 謝謝
- You want a cup? - Appreciate it.
這咖啡放了多久了?
How fresh is that coffee?
通常我每周煮一次
I generally make a fresh pot every week,
即使有剩下的
even if there's some left over.
那個槍殺你的死在牢堣F
That man that shot you died in prison?
安哥拉 是的
Angola. Yeah.
若是他被釋放出來 你會怎麼做?
What'd you done he'd a been released?
我不知道  什麼也不會做
Oh, I don't know. Nothing.
我也從來沒想過
Wouldn't be no point in it.
我真的驚訝你會這麼說
Kindly surprised to hear you say that.
嗯 當你試圖拿回...
Well, all the time you spend trying to get back
失去的東西的時候
what's been took from you,
也將會失去更多
more is going out the door.
不久之後
After a while,
你就只會試著綁條止血帶
you have to try to get a tourniquet on it.
你祖父從未要求我 要我擔任副警長
Your granddad never asked me to sign on as a deputy.
洛蕾塔說你要辭職了
Loretta tells me you're quittin'.
為何要辭職?
How come you doing that?
我不知道
I don't know.
我感到心力交瘁
I feel overmatched.
我總是想 當我老了
I always figured when I got older,
上帝會用某種方式進入我心中
God would... sort of come into my life somehow.
他沒有
And He didn't.
我也不會怪上帝
And I don't blame Him.
換作我是他
If I was Him,
我也會是一樣的看法
I'd have the same opinion of me that He does.
你不會知道上帝想些什麼
You don't know what He thinks.
我將麥克叔叔的警徽與臂章...
I sent Uncle Mac's thumbbuster and badge...
送到巡警署
over to the Rangers,
放到了博物館
put it in their museum.
你爸爸告訴過你...
Your daddy ever tell you...
麥克叔叔如何得到勳章的嗎?
how Uncle Mac come to his reward?
在哈得斯佩斯郡的家門口 被槍殺倒地
Gunned down on his own porch over in Hudspeth County.
共有七八個人
Seven or eight of 'em come up there,
想要這 想要那
all wanting this, wanting that.
麥克叔叔走進屋子去拿出散彈鎗
Uncle Mac went back in the house to get the shotgun.
他們比他快一步
Well, they was ahead of him.
在門口把他殺死了
Shot him in his doorway.
愛拉姑姑出來想要止住流血
Aunt Ella come out, tried to stop the bleeding.
麥克叔叔還在想要拿他的散彈鎗
Uncle Mac all the while trying to get that shotgun.
他們就坐在馬上
They just sat there on their horses,
看著他死去
watching him die.
稍後...
After a while,
其中一個人說了些印第安話 他們才轉身
one of 'em said something in Indian and they turned.
離開
Left out.
嗯 麥克叔叔知道狀況的危險 即使愛拉姑姑沒有意識到
Uncle Mac knew the score, even if Aunt Ella didn't.
子彈射穿左肺
Shot through the left lung.
事情就是那樣 就如他們說的
And that was that... as they say.
他何時死的?
When'd he die?
190...9年
Nineteen zero and, uh... nine?
不 我是說立刻還是晚上 還是...
No, I mean, was it right away or in the night or...
- 什麼時候? - 我想是當天晚上
- When was it? - I believe it was that night.
她隔天早上就把他埋葬了
She buried him the next morning.
在那硬硬的黏土層用力挖掘
Digging in that hard old caliche.
你聽到的並不是什麼新鮮事
What you got ain't nothin' new.
這國家對待人民很苛刻
This country is hard on people.
對於將要發生的事情 你也無法阻擋
You can't stop what's coming.
沒有人會拜訪你
It ain't all waitin' on you.
一切都是空虛的
That's vanity.
我知道這事情還沒了結
I knew this wasn't done with.
我沒拿到那些錢
I ain't got the money.
我身邊的錢也所剩無幾
What little I had is long gone...
很多帳單沒付
and there's bills aplenty to pay yet.
今天才埋葬了我母親
I buried my mother today.
喪葬費用也還沒付
Ain't paid for that neither.
我不擔心那個
I wouldn't worry about it.
我要坐下來
I need to sit down.
你沒有理由傷害我
You got no cause to hurt me.
沒有 但我承諾過
No. But I gave my word.
- 你承諾過? - 對你丈夫
- You gave your word? - To your husband.
沒有道理啊
That don't make sense.
你對我丈夫承諾過要殺我?
You gave your word to my husband to kill me?
你丈夫原本有機會救你
Your husband had the opportunity to save you.
可是 他利用你 想要救他自己
Instead, he used you to try to save himself.
不是那樣
Not like that.
不是你說的那樣
Not like you say.
你不需要這樣做
You don't have to do this.
人們都是這樣說
People always say the same thing.
說些什麼?
What do they say?
人們都說:"你不需要這樣做"
They say, "You don't have to do this."
- 你不必這樣 - 好吧
- You don't. - OK.
這是我能做得最好的事
This is the best I can do.
猜吧
Call it.
我看你坐在那邊的時候 我就知道你瘋了
I knowed you was crazy when I saw you sitting there.
我很確認我知道要發生的事情
I knowed exactly what was in store for me.
- 猜吧 - 不
- Call it. - No.
我不會猜的
I ain't gonna call it.
猜吧
Call it.
這硬幣什麼也不會說
The coin don't have no say.
只有你
It's just you.
嗯 我來的路跟這個硬幣一樣
Well, I got here the same way the coin did.
先生 你的骨頭裂出來了
Mister, you got a bone sticking out of your arm.
我還好 讓我在這塈仍X分鐘
I'm all right. Let me just sit here a minute.
救護車就在路上 是那邊的男子去打的電話
There's an ambulance coming. The man went to call.
好的
All right.
你還好嗎?
Are you all right?
你的骨頭裂出來了
You got a bone sticking out your arm.
你的襯衫怎麼賣?
What'll you take for the shirt?
先生 我可以送給你
Well, hell, mister, I'll give you my shirt.
看那恐怖的骨頭
Look at that fucking bone.
幫我打個結
Tie this for me.
就打個結 就打個結
Just tie it, just tie it.
先生 聽著 我很樂於助人
Hell,mister.Look,I don't mind helping someone out.
- 那可不是小錢 - 收下吧
- That's a lot of money. - Take it.
收下 然後...你們沒見到我
Take it and... you didn't see me.
我已經不見了
I was already gone.
是 先生
Yes, sir.
見者也有份
Part of that's mine, right?
又不是你的襯衫
You still got your damn shirt.
他的錢不只是要買襯衫
Ain't even what it was for.
也許吧 但是是我的襯衫給了他
Maybe. But I'm still out a shirt.
- 或許我要繼續騎馬 - 好吧
- Maybe I'll go ridin'. - OK.
- 你覺得呢? - 我無法幫你計劃一天要做的事
- What do you think? - Well, I can't plan your day.
我是說 你也想一起來嗎?
I mean, would you care to join me?
不了 我又還沒退休
Lord, no, I'm not retired.
- 不然我在這媕飢A - 呃...最好不要
- Maybe I'll help out here then. - Uh...better not.
- 睡得好嗎? - 我不知道 做了夢
- How'd you sleep? - I don't know. Had dreams.
你現在有時間做夢了
Well, you got time for 'em now.
有什麼有趣的嗎?
Anything interesting?
只有當事人會有興趣
They always is to the party concerned.
愛德·湯姆 我願洗耳恭聽
Ed Tom, I'll be polite.
好吧 有兩段夢
All right, then. Two of 'em,
都跟我爸有關 很怪
both had my father in 'em. It's peculiar.
我夢堣韖L要老20歲
I'm older now than he ever was by 20 years.
所以 可以說他比我年輕
So, in a sense, he's the younger man.
沒關係 第一個夢記不太清楚 但...
Anyway, the first one I don't remember too well,
是關於在城堿Y處和他相見
but it was about meeting him in town,
他給了我一些錢
somewheres, and he give me some money.
我想我弄丟了
I think I lost it.
第二個夢
Second one,
我跟爸都回到舊時過去
it was like we was both back in older times.
某個夜晚
And I was a-horseback,
我騎馬穿過山上小路
going through the mountains of a night.
穿過山上的小徑
Going through this pass in the mountains.
天氣很冷 地上有雪
It was cold, and there was snow on the ground.
他騎馬超過我 繼續往前
And he rode past me and kept on going,
什麼也沒說只是繼續往前騎
never said nothing going by, just rode on past.
他從頭到腳都用毯子蓋著...
He had his blanket wrapped around him...
並且頭朝下
and his head down.
當他超過我身邊時
When he rode past,
我見到他拿著一把牛角火炬
I seen he was carrying fire in a horn,
就像從前人們一樣 而且我...
the way people used to do, and I...
我從火光堨i以將牛角看的很清楚
I could see the horn from the light inside of it,
就跟月亮的顏色一樣
'bout the color of the moon.
在夢 我知道他將
And, in the dream, I knew that he was...
繼續往前騎去
...going on ahead.
好像他要在寒冷的黑夜...
He was fixin' to make a fire...
到某處去生火
somewhere out there in all that dark and cold.
我知道 無論何時我到了那 他都會在那
And I knew that whenever I got there, he'd be there.
然後 我就醒了
And then I woke up.